const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",a="crk",o=200,i=120,t=[{id:1086,question:"As they were sharing Christ’s sufferings, Peter advised Christians to",option:{a:"be prayerful       ",b:"rejoice       ",c:"be trustful ",d:"persevere"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:284,question:"After Prophet Ezekiel had eaten what he was offered, he was sent to speak to",option:{a:"a people of hard language",b:"the house of Israel",c:"the house of Judah",d:"a people of foreign language"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:747,question:"The core of Saul's disobedience was that___________",option:{a:"He didn't perform the task of smiting the Amalekites to the letter",b:"He preserved the booty for himself",c:"He freed the Kenites",d:"He refused to carry out God's assignment on eliminating the Amalekites"},section:"",image:"",answer:" a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:558,question:"Elijah destroyed the prophets of Baal",option:{a:"to oppose Baal worship.",b:"as an act of revenge.",c:"as an act of sacrifice.",d:"to shame Jezebel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:276,question:"“My spirit shall not abide in man forever, for he is flesh...” When God made the statement above, He concluded that man’s days shall be",option:{a:"one hundred years",b:"one hundred and fifty years",c:"eighty years",d:"one hundred and twenty years."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:172,question:"Render to Caesar the things that they are Caesar’s and to God the things are God’s, the above quotation emphasizes  ",option:{a:"Obedience to divine authority  ",b:"Striking a balance between civil and divine authorities ",c:"Disobedience to civil authority  ",d:"Total rejection of both divine and civil authorities"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:86,question:"The conversion of Paul was made possible by",option:{a:"Simeon ",b:"Zacchaccus ",c:"the risen Lord ",d:"Mathew "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:16,question:"The mother of Esau is ",option:{a:"Ruth ",b:"Ester ",c:"Rebecca ",d:"Jezebel  "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:611,question:"Although Josiah removed the vessels of Baal and Asherah from the Temple, God did not turn from the fierceness of His 	wrath because”",option:{a:"the people did not remove them completely",b:"Jehoahaz, Josiah’s son, had provoked Him",c:"Manasseh had provoked Him",d:"the people had opposed Josiah."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:24,question:"He shall save his people from their sins. Who is being referred to here? ",option:{a:"John the Baptist ",b:"Elijah ",c:"Elisha ",d:"Jesus                              "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:622,question:"‘Depart from me, for l am a sinful man, oh Lord.’ This statement was uttered by Peter at the",option:{a:"last supper",b:"garden of Gethsemane",c:"call of the disciples",d:"transfiguration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:1003,question:"David bitterly mourned when Abner was slain by  ",option:{a:"Ishbosheth",b:".       Absalom",c:"Asahel",d:"Joab."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:683,question:"Paul in Romans declared “for as by one man’s disobedience many were made sinners, so by one man’s obedience many will be made...”",option:{a:"innocent.",b:"righteous.",c:"faithful.",d:"Christians."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:219,question:"According to Jesus, the seventy disciples who returned from a successful missionary work should rejoice because",option:{a:"the demons were subject to them",b:"the sick were healed through their ministry",c:"the lame walked just at their command",d:"their names were written in heaven"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:378,question:"Believers according to Jesus in John’s gospel, become his friends, if they imbibe his teaching on",option:{a:"forgiveness",b:"obedience",c:"love",d:"faith."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:412,question:"King Josiah was killed by Pharaoh Neco in a battle at",option:{a:"Syria",b:"Meggiddo",c:"Megiddo",d:"Egypt."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:905,question:"Your love is like the morning cloud, like the dew that goes early”. What did Hosea mean by this statement? ",option:{a:"Israel’s relationship with God was shortlived ",b:"Israel did not truly love God as she should ",c:"Israel did had love for other gods ",d:"Israel had no love for God"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:108,question:"The commander of David’s army was ",option:{a:"Abner ",b:"Joab ",c:"Abiathar ",d:"Adonijah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:714,question:".I desire steadfast love and not sacrifice, offerings”. This statement was the central theme of the prophecy of __________.",option:{a:"Elijah",b:"Ezekiel",c:"Hosea",d:"Isaiah"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:148,question:"In his second letter to the Christians in Thessalonians, Paul admonished them to have nothing to do with anyone who refused to obey what he wrote in the letter. What did Paul think would happen to the person?  ",option:{a:"The person would be encouraged  ",b:"The person would be ashamed  ",c:"The person would be disturbed  ",d:"The person would repent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:823,question:"When the apostles in Jerusalem heard that Samaria had received the gospel, they sent to them   ",option:{a:"Mark and Barnabas. ",b:"Peter and John. ",c:"Paul and John. ",d:"Peter and Paul."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:701,question:"________ was the man James used as example of how the effective prayer of the righteous man works",option:{a:"Jesus Christ",b:"Peter",c:"Paul",d:"Elijah"},section:"",image:"",answer:" d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:251,question:"In Romans, Paul condemned sin taking over mortal bodies in the new life as instruments of",option:{a:"greediness",b:"wickedness",c:"sadness",d:"foolishness."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:653,question:"The sons of Eli were regarded as worthless men for all the following reasons except",option:{a:"sleeping with the women at the tent of meeting",b:"failing to attend the places of worship regularly.",c:"taking the meat for sacrifice before boiling.",d:"showing no respect for God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:953,question:"God promised to punish the house of Ahab and not Ahab himself, because he",option:{a:"humbled himself. ",b:"acted under pressure. ",c:"was a righteous man. ",d:"acted wisely."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:104,question:"Each of these spies sent out by Moses on God’s command to report on the nature of the promised land was a ",option:{a:"great warrior ",b:"wise judge ",c:"priest ",d:"leaders in his own tribe"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:466,question:"God spoke through Amos that He would punish Israel for the following sins except that they",option:{a:"sold the righteous for silver.",b:"sold the needy for a pair of shoes.",c:"trampled the head of the poor into the dust.",d:"pursued their brothers with the swords."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:509,question:"God fed the Israelites with Manna at the wilderness of",option:{a:"Zin",b:"Elim",c:"Sinai",d:"Sin"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:274,question:"“1 will not eat until I have told my errand” In the statement above, the errand of Abraham’s servant was to",option:{a:"find a wife for Isaac",b:"deliver the camels to Laban",c:"assess Isaac’s future wife",d:"deliver Isaac’s message to Laban"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:741,question:'"I gave you cleanness of teeth in all your cities". By this statement, God gave them ______',option:{a:"New set of teeth",b:"No food to eat",c:"No water to drink",d:"No teeth at all"},section:"",image:"",answer:" b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:691,question:"Paul, pleaded with Philemon to forgive",option:{a:"Barnabas.",b:"Timothy.",c:"Onesimus.",d:"Silas"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:989,question:"Which of Paul’s epistle was written to an individual?",option:{a:"Romans ",b:"Corinthians   ",c:"Colossians    ",d:"Philemon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:331,question:"“Tell people, His disciples came by night and stole him away while we were asleep...” The intention of the speaker in the statement above was to",option:{a:"implicate the disciples",b:"absolve the soldiers from all blame",c:"deny the resurrection story",d:"convince the authority"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:1072,question:" Cleopas’ heart burnt within him on the road to Emmaus when Jesus",option:{a:"appeared to them      ",b:"taught them the scriptures ",c:"broke bread with them    ",d:"walked with them"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:413,question:"The major reason God allowed the Babylonian attack on the city of Jerusalem was to",option:{a:"demonstrate the ability of God to deliver His people from captivity",b:"set a trap for the Babylonians and destroy them",c:"restore the people of Judah and their leaders to the true worship of God",d:"punish the people of Judah and their leaders for their sins."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:235,question:"Paul said he was not fit to be called an apostle because he",option:{a:"was not called like the others",b:"was not a Jew",c:"persecuted the Early Church",d:"was only a distributor of letters"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:211,question:"Who among the prophets was referred to as a prophet of doom?",option:{a:"Isaiah",b:"Ezekiel",c:"Amos",d:"Jeremiah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:589,question:"In which of the following ways did the Philippians share in Paul’s suffering while in prison?",option:{a:"Appealing for the release of Paul",b:"Sending him relief materials",c:"Continuing in prayer for him",d:"Remaining in partnership with him in receiving."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:687,question:"‘Death is swallowed up in victory, “oh death, where is your victory”? This statement is found in the book of",option:{a:"Corinthians.",b:"Romans.",c:"Galatians.",d:"Philemon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:479,question:"John’s summary of God’s love for the world is that He",option:{a:"sent his son to judge the world righteously.",b:"created man in his own image with authority.",c:"made light that the world might walk in it.",d:"gave his only son to save all believers."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:695,question:"James advised Christians to portray their faith in Jesus by",option:{a:"listening to the word of God always.",b:"converting others to Christ.",c:"practicalizing their Christian belief",d:"constant prayer and fasting."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:403,question:"David’s inaction at Ammon’s incest with Tamar showed his",option:{a:"lack of control over his children",b:"excessive love for Ammon",c:"ability to forgive as a leader",d:"wisdom and strength of character"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:671,question:"The incidents that took place following Jesus’ death on the cross did not include the",option:{a:"tearing into two of the temple’s veil.",b:"quaking of the earth that broke the rocks.",c:"the opening of the tombs.",d:"trembling of the chief priest and his conversion."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:540,question:"One of the prophets that prophesied hope for Israel in spite of God’s promise of punishment was",option:{a:"Amos",b:"Jeremiah",c:"Obadiah",d:"Hosea"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:592,question:"Why did Paul wish to retain Onesimus?",option:{a:"To protect him from persecution",b:"Christianity was opposed to slavery",c:"Philemon had earnestly requested that from Paul",d:"To serve him during his imprisonment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:426,question:"The promise to those who are persecuted for righteousness sake is that they will",option:{a:"inherit the earth",b:"inherit the kingdom of heaven",c:"see God",d:"be called sons of God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:62,question:"Who was the priest that confronted Uzziah in the temple ",option:{a:"Zadokaul ",b:"Phineas ",c:"Azariah ",d:"Aaron"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:1042,question:"Which of the following was not a river flowing from the Garden of Eden? ",option:{a:"  Gibon     ",b:"  Tigris     ",c:"   Euphrates         ",d:"Kishon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:34,question:"The last things which Zedekiah saw before his eyes were removed was the ",option:{a:"Egyptian army ",b:"slaughter of all his sons ",c:"city of Jerusalem ",d:"feasting of the children of Israel "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:880,question:"To which religious party did Gamaliel belong? The",option:{a:"Zealots",b:"Sadducees",c:"Pharisees      ",d:"Herodians"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:998,question:"The sons of Eli were regarded as worthless men for all the ",option:{a:"sleeping with the women at the tent of meeting. ",b:"failing to attend the places of worship regularly. ",c:"taking the meat for sacrifice before boiling. ",d:"showing no respect for God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:751,question:"According to St James, 'He who keeps the whole law and fails in one is guilty of....'",option:{a:"Breaking the new commandment of Christ",b:"Breaking that particular love and should pray for grace",c:"Breaking the whole law",d:"Breaking the ten commandments"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:1016,question:"The incidents that took place following Jesus’ death on the cross did not include the ",option:{a:"tearing into two of the temple’s veil. ",b:"quaking of the earth that broke the rocks. ",c:"the opening of the tombs. ",d:"trembling of the chief priest and his conversion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:670,question:"Peter called for the construction of three booths for Jesus, Moses and Elijah, respectively during",option:{a:"the transfiguration.",b:"the Ascension.",c:"Jesus’ arrest.",d:"the Passover feast."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:1057,question:"Gehazi became a leper because of his",option:{a:"deceitfulness   ",b:"greed    ",c:"wickedness         ",d:"lies"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:341,question:"In Corinthians, Paul stated that by one Spirit we were",option:{a:"free from bondage of sin",b:"united into one church",c:"committee to Christian service",d:"baptized into one body"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:544,question:"God’s message through Jonah’s was to the people of",option:{a:"Joppa",b:"Tarshish",c:"Samaira",d:"Nineveh"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:232,question:"Paul argued that Jesus died for us while we were yet sinners in order to",option:{a:"prove that he was not an ordinary man",b:"show Gods’ love for sinful man",c:"warn us to desist from sin",d:"give us power to possess the earth"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:672,question:"“How is it that you a Jew ask a drink of me...” This statement was made by the",option:{a:"Gentile woman.",b:"woman of Samaria.",c:"possessed woman.",d:"woman of Galilee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:337,question:"Paul in Romans stated that the righteousness of God has been manifested through",option:{a:"the Law",b:"the priests",c:"faith in Jesus",d:"Temple sacrifices."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:78,question:"In order that Benjamin might be brought to Egypt, Joseph detained ",option:{a:"Ruben ",b:"Levi ",c:"Jacob ",d:"Simoen "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:56,question:"He shall save his people from their sins. Who is being referred to here? ",option:{a:"John the Baptist ",b:"Elijah ",c:"Elisha ",d:"Jesus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:654,question:"Who was the first king of Israel?",option:{a:"Kish",b:"David",c:"Solomon",d:"Saul"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:852,question:"Samuel said that rebellion was as the sin of divination just as stubbornness was as ",option:{a:"iniquity and adultery",b:" sinful as disobedience",c:"iniquity and murder",d:"sinful as adultery"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:184,question:"One of the following is not in the Pentateuch  ",option:{a:"Exodus    ",b:"Judges     ",c:"Leviticus   ",d:"Numbers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:874,question:"Discipline requires self- denial and complete",option:{a:"tolerance ",b:"forgiveness",c:"commitment",d:"purification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:258,question:"In the country of the Gerasenes, Jesus healed the",option:{a:"man possessed of demons",b:"paralytic at the pool",c:"leper",d:"blind man."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:517,question:"An action that demonstrated Solomon’s wisdom was his",option:{a:"judgment of the prostitute’s child",b:"reliance on a medium",c:"alliance with other nations",d:"taxation policy for his building works"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:570,question:"The parable of the rich man and Lazarus indicates that",option:{a:"poverty is a mark of righteousness.",b:"death is a leveler for rich and poor",c:"only poor people will die physically.",d:"all rich men are going to hell fire."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:967,question:"The initial evidence that the disciples had received the Holy Spirit was",option:{a:"performing miracles",b:"preaching to the people. ",c:"speaking in tongues. ",d:"praying together"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:1085,question:"James advised against looking down on the poor because they are",option:{a:"the rightful heirs of the kingdom ",b:"those who spent time on the Lord",c:"for peace and self sacrifice",d:"those who contribute little but do a lot"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:1023,question:"Saul was converted on his journey to  ",option:{a:"Samaria                  ",b:" Jerusalem.",c:"  Salamis.",d:" Damascus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:109,question:"That was the sin of David that involved Bathseba? ",option:{a:"Murder ",b:"adultery ",c:"dishonesty ",d:"arrogance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:32,question:"Daniel was delivered from the den of lions for all the following reason except ",option:{a:"his holiness and faith ",b:"his kindness ",c:"God’s love for him ",d:"God’s mighty power"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:50,question:"Daniel was delivered from the den of lion for all the following reason except ",option:{a:"his holiness and faith ",b:"his kindness ",c:"God’s love for him ",d:"God’s mighty power."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:111,question:"What specific reply did John the Baptist give to the soldiers during his preaching ",option:{a:"collect no more than is appointed you ",b:"do not begin to say to yourselves: we have Abraham as our father ",c:"bear fruits that befit repentance ",d:"be content with your wages"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:878,question:"The resurrection stroy encourage Christians to believe that the Lord they adore is",option:{a:"still alive today",b:"a miracle working God",c:"Lord over evils",d:"powerful and Just"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:904,question:"According to Daniel the command of Nebuchadnezzar to worship the golden image amounted to ",option:{a:" profanity      ",b:"idolatry.     ",c:"sacrilege",d:"abomination"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:472,question:"Jesus teaches, “Let your light so shine before men...” By light Jesus refers to,",option:{a:"the Christian character and virtues in us.",b:"the bright lights at the altar in the church.",c:"the light that shows the right way.",d:"our knowledge of the scripture."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:669,question:"“My son your sins are forgiven”. These were the words of Jesus to the",option:{a:"demoniac.",b:"paralytic.",c:"man born blind",d:"centurion’s servant."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:853,question:"“Has the Lord as great delight in burnt offerings and sacrifices as in obeying the voice of Lord? These words were directed to king",option:{a:"Ahab",b:"Saul",c:"Agag",d:"David"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:577,question:"The descent of the Holy Spirit on the day of  Pentecost was prophesied by",option:{a:"Amos.",b:"Joel.",c:"David.",d:"Ezekiel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:586,question:"Paul’s greatest writing about spiritual gift is found in his letter to the",option:{a:"Galatians.",b:"Ephesians.",c:"Romans.",d:"Corinthians"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:771,question:"In the Gospel according to St. Matthew, Jesus sent His disciples to_______",option:{a:"the Gentiles",b:"the Samaritans",c:"the Jews",d:"the Greeks"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:405,question:"Because David sought God’s will to pursue the Amalekites 	who had invaded Ziklag, he was rewarded with victory and",option:{a:"many new territories",b:"spoils",c:"many prisoners of war",d:"favour"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:554,question:"When Abner wanted to transfer his allegiance to David, the latter gave him the condition to",option:{a:"openly submit to Joab.",b:"convince all Israel to come over to David.",c:"restore his wife Michal to him.",d:"slay Ishbosheth. Saul’s successor."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:458,question:"When God ordered famine on Israel, Elijah was fed by the ravens at",option:{a:"Brook Cherith.",b:"River Jordan.",c:"River Kishon",d:"Mount Carmel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:123,question:"What Josiah, the king of Judah, is best remembered for in Jewish history is ",option:{a:"His ability to destroy all the shine of Baals",b:"His order that the bones and tombs of the prophets of God must be preserved ",c:"His strong opposition to Pharaoh-Neco of Egypt ",d:"His reparation of the temples of God"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:193,question:"One of the following is not among the “I am” Sayings of Jesus  ",option:{a:"I am the bread of life",b:"I am the gate of life",c:"I am the good shepherd",d:"I am the way"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:767,question:"The Egyptians encamped at ____ when they pursued the Israelites",option:{a:"Raphidim",b:"The sea",c:"Pi-ha-hi-roth",d:"The wilderness of Sin"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:649,question:"The name Moses means",option:{a:"baptized in water",b:"abandoned in water.",c:"drawn out of water.",d:"thrown into water."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:239,question:"Which of the following does not relate to the new life in Christ?",option:{a:"Baptism",b:"Circumcision",c:"Grace of God",d:"Faith"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:984,question:"Paul believes that the resurrection of the dead would only occur on the",option:{a:"last day.",b:"triumphant day.",c:"ascension day",d:"pentecost day."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:632,question:"‘...Why has Satan filled your heart to lie to the Holy Spirit..’ Peter rebuked Ananias in the statement above for his sin of (Acts 5:3-4)",option:{a:"greed",b:"insincerity",c:"covetousness",d:"partiality."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:1012,question:" “And I asked them concerning the Jews that survived, who has escaped exile, and concerning Jerusalem...” These were   the words of ",option:{a:"Jeremiah. ",b:"  Nehemiah ",c:" Ezr",d:"Hanani"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:946,question:"When the people of Israel received the minority report from the spies, they decided to",option:{a:"kill Moses for taking them out ress at Sheehem was of Egypt to ",b:"go back to Egypt. ",c:"choose Caleb as their new leader",d:"stone the two spies to death."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:476,question:"“No one can serve two masters...” This means that one should not",option:{a:"be idolatrous.",b:"belong to two religions.",c:"worship money.",d:"bean unbeliever."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:208,question:"Nebuchadnezzar punished those who refused to worship the golden image by throwing them into",option:{a:"the River Nile",b:"the rivers of  Babylon",c:"a furnace",d:"a lion’s den"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:721,question:"St Paul's condition for the attainment of justification is by ______?",option:{a:"Total obedience to the law",b:"Holiness in Christ Jesus",c:"Faith in the Resurrected Jesus",d:"Loving our Christian brethren"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:4,question:"The thief as described by Jesus comes to ",option:{a:"destroy, kill and steal ",b:"destroy, steal and kill ",c:"kill, destroy and kill ",d:"steal, kill and destroy "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:345,question:"According to James, treatment of brethren at fellowship should not be based on",option:{a:"appearance",b:"sentiments",c:"gender",d:"age."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:1039,question:"According to Paul in Galatians, law ceased to be our custodian as soon as ",option:{a:"it was made available to us. ",b:"Christ adopted us as his children.     ",c:"we adopted the faith of Abraham.    ",d:"we stopped worshipping the elemental spirits"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:778,question:"The most significant lesson at the scene of the Israelites' blame of Moses in their struggle and escape from Egypt is that___________",option:{a:"God hardened the heart of Pharaoh to pursue the Israelites",b:"they would have perfered to stay back and die in Egypt",c:"Moses' courage and confidence in God saved the entire situation",d:"Moses' height of anger and intolerance was revealed"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:486,question:"Paul’s teaching in Colossians on love, respect and obedience concerns",option:{a:"Christian giving.",b:"family relationship.",c:"master servant relationship.",d:"Christian relations with their enemies."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:1067,question:" “Don’t be afraid, henceforth you will be catching men”. “Catching men” means capturing men ",option:{a:"to the new faith         ",b:"    who oppose the Gospel ",c:"who are sinful ",d:"who are spiritual"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:178,question:"Who was the secretary employed by Jeremiah to write his prophecy?",option:{a:"Amanuensis  ",b:"Amos  ",c:"Baruch  ",d:"Joshua"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:1084,question:"James taught that Christians should offer prayers of thanksgiving when they are ",option:{a:"remorseful   ",b:"sick    ",c:"interceding ",d:"cheerful"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:658,question:"David bitterly mourned when Abner was slain by",option:{a:"Ishbosheth.",b:"Absalom.",c:"Asahel.",d:"Joab."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:255,question:"According to Matthew, the stone on the tomb of Jesus was removed by",option:{a:"an angel",b:"a Roman soldier",c:"Mary Magdalene",d:"Peter and John."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:903,question:"The Israelites under Barak defeated the Canaanite troops led by ",option:{a:"Jael",b:"  Siser         ",c:" Abinoam",d:"Heber"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:61,question:"The king of Persia who made it possible for the return of the exiles form Babylon was ",option:{a:"Dairus ",b:"Cyrus ",c:"Zechariah ",d:"Zerubabel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:562,question:"Daniel was delivered from the lion’s den because",option:{a:"of his faith in God’s power.",b:"of the king’s prayers.",c:"he was able to charm the lions.",d:"the lions were kind to him."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:1063,question:"The indigenous official of King Darius were unhappy with Daniel because he ",option:{a:"often reported them to the King ",b:"was a Jewish exile         ",c:" had an excel lent spirit ",d:"refused to worship the golden image"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:749,question:"One derivative lesson from the story of Gehazi'z greed is that_______",option:{a:"We can by ourselves, through materialism, cause the destruction of generations yet unborn",b:"Dishonesty should not have been a ground for cursing Gehazi with leprosy",c:"As servants of God we must endeavour not to readily demand gifts from those we help",d:"We should be wary of accepting gifts from the unrighteous"},section:"",image:"",answer:" a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:608,question:"The prophet who made known the imminent divi¬sion of the kingdom of Israel during Solomon’s reign was",option:{a:"Jehu",b:"Ahijah",c:"Elisha",d:"Elijah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:937,question:"According to Paul’s teaching in Galatians, Christian become sons of God by ",option:{a:"According to Paul’s teaching in Galatians, Christian become sons of God by ",b:"adoption of Judaism",c:"being Abraham’s descendants.",d:"works of faith."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:159,question:"Who was one of the Seven Deacons who had four daughters who were prophetesses?  ",option:{a:"Nicolaus  ",b:"Stephen  ",c:"Prochorus  ",d:"Philip "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:931,question:"Paul believes that spiritual gifts are of great advantage to the Church because they ",option:{a:"enhance the beauty of the Church. ",b:"promote growth in diverse ways. ",c:"lead to talent development. ",d:"help the individual to be active"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:595,question:"Peter recommends submission to the civil authority so as to",option:{a:"silence the ungodly.",b:"encourage the believers.",c:"promote faith in God.",d:"live as free men."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:389,question:"In Romans, Paul taught that where there is no law, there is no",option:{a:"transgression",b:"peace",c:"reward",d:"punishment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"}],s={message:e,subject:a,status:200,total:120,data:t};export{t as data,s as default,e as message,o as status,a as subject,i as total};
